<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>library(dplyr) liftdatraw1 &amp;lt;- readr::read_csv(&amp;quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday/master/data/2019/2019-10-08/ipf_lifts.csv&amp;quot;) liftdataraw2&amp;lt;-na.omit(liftdatraw1) liftdata&amp;lt;-liftdataraw2%&amp;gt;%select(sex,event,equipment,age,division,&amp;quot;bodyweight&amp;quot;=bodyweight_kg,&amp;quot;best3squat&amp;quot;=best3squat_kg,&amp;quot;best3bench&amp;quot;=best3bench_kg,&amp;quot;best3deadlift&amp;quot;=best3deadlift_kg,place) liftdata3&amp;lt;-liftdataraw2%&amp;gt;%select(sex, &amp;quot;bodyweight&amp;quot;=bodyweight_kg, &amp;quot;maxsquat&amp;quot;=best3squat_kg, &amp;quot;maxbench&amp;quot;=best3bench_kg, &amp;quot;maxdead&amp;quot;=best3deadlift_kg, equipment) liftdata &amp;lt;- liftdata[!is.na(as.numeric(as.character(liftdata$place))),] My dataset was found from GitHub’s Tidy Tuesday website and it contained information about powerlifting. Data about powerlifting competitions over time are included in the dataset. I will be focusing on seven of the variables described: bodyweight, sex, equipment type, place, max weight on three reps of deadlift, max weight on three repos of bench press, and max weight on thee reps of squats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal interests</title>
      <link>/blog/personal-interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/personal-interests/</guid>
      <description>Aside from my professional interests, I am an out going guy that likes to live life to the fullest. I believe that we live to learn and to explore. With that said, I often find myself exploring various hobbies such as learning musical instruments, exploring nature, and digital arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software interest</title>
      <link>/blog/software-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/software-interest/</guid>
      <description>I discovered my interest in software as I progressed through college. I began to find myself pursuing varying personal projects to enrich my knowledge in the field. These projects had brought me much joy and I decided that I wanted to pursue a career in software engineering. I like to live a life full of adventure and will always be interested to learn new things and to explore new career opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>For the exploratory analysis project performed, I chose to combine two datasets by the country variable. The first dataset I chose was about average plastic waste per country that was measured in kg/person/day. The first dataset was obtained from GitHub’s tidytuesday project. In addition to containing average plastic waste, the first dataset also included the country’s three letter code, the GDP per capital of each country in the data set, year, and total population of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>